<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>IOTABOTS Blog</title>
        <link>https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/blog</link>
        <description>IOTABOTS Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Welcome to IOTABOTS]]></title>
            <link>https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/blog/hello-world</link>
            <guid>hello-world</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Announcement of the new IOTABOTS blog.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>IOTABOTS prints Hello World!</p><p>Welcome to the IOTABOTS blog. Here you will get the hotest news and updates about our progress and whats going on in the community. Learn more about IOTABOTS in this blog article!</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="bee-bob-boo"><em>BEE</em> <em>BOB</em> *BOO**<a class="hash-link" href="#bee-bob-boo" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h4><p>On the 2nd November 2021, the first 500 IOTABOTS NFTs were minted for free and feeless on the public IOTA Smart Contracts EVM Testnet. The IOTABOTS project was born on a weekend project and became one of the most liked NFT projects on the IOTA Ecosystem. We will explain here, how the team did this and inspired other NFT artists and developers to bring their projects to IOTA: </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="what-are-iotabots">What are IOTABOTS?<a class="hash-link" href="#what-are-iotabots" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>IOTABOTS are Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs) based on the common ERC721 Token standard. There are 10.000 unique IOTABOTS with different colours, shapes and emotions. Each IOTABOT has also a unique number. The older the number, the older the bot.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="one-weekend---idea-to-drop">One Weekend - Idea to Drop<a class="hash-link" href="#one-weekend---idea-to-drop" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Yes - everything you saw on the first drop was created over a (long) weekend. The Idea, the beautiful 3D graphics, the landing page and the minting website, to give away the NFTs to the IOTA community. The bots are created with a generator and X different traits, which are different parts of the image, like background colour, robot shabe or the display. We just followed a Youtube tutorial and it worked! The first drop with 500 Bots were sld our in less than fifteen minutes - and we just send a message in the IOTA Discord.</p><p>Because the idea behind this was to discover NFTs on IOTA, we did not think about the day after the drop. We discovered that the Tesnet is not very stable and could be resettet sometimes. This lead to the #safeTheBots initiative, which was founded by some community developers with the goal that everyone can hold their bots and with a successful transition to the later mainet. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="nft-on-a-testnet-how-does-this-work">NFT on a Testnet, how does this work?<a class="hash-link" href="#nft-on-a-testnet-how-does-this-work" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>IOTA Smart Contracts are in a beta stage and a public testnet is provided by the IOTA Foundation. Such an early environment is prone to errors and many things can go wrong. The Testnet even becomes a reset sometimes, which removes all transactions, and also all NFTs. With the #saveTheBots initiative we stored all NFT identifiers and assigned them to their owner addresses. So we have basically a list, which address has which IOTABOTs. After a chain reset, we deploy the NFT Smart Contract again and airdrop the NFTs to their holder with a custom script. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="our-mission">Our mission<a class="hash-link" href="#our-mission" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>This project inspired a lot of people to discover NFTs on IOTA which we did not expect and we really liked! We see ourselves as pioneers which share our results and learnings. We love open-source and are open to connect with you and your project to empower the IOTA ecosystem.</p><p>If you also feel inspired, have fun and good luck with your project and get in touch with us! We always search for new pioneers in our team!</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="bee-bob-boo-1"><em>BEE</em> <em>BOB</em> <em>BOO</em><a class="hash-link" href="#bee-bob-boo-1" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h4><p>Pro Tip: This blog is created with <a href="https://docusaurus.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Docusaurus 2</strong></a> like the <a href="https://wiki.iota.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IOTA Wiki</a> ❤️</p><hr><p>Your welcome to join our <a href="https://discord.gg/iotabots" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> and follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/iotabots" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hello</category>
            <category>announcement</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>